paessler.com 2019-12-11

# Paessler AG Privacy Policy

### A - GENERAL INFORMATION FOR THE PROCESSING OF YOUR DATA

1\. Responsible entity and contact

Responsible for the data processing as described here is Paessler AG.

Postal address: Paessler AG, Thurn-und-Taxis-Str. 14, 90411 Nuremberg   
Email: [[email protected]](https://www.paessler.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#40292e262f0030212533332c25326e232f2d)   
Tel: +49 911 93775-0

Company data protection officer is Sebastian Bonhag. Contact him via email to [[email protected]](https://www.paessler.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#f181839887909288b181909482829d9483df929e9c) or letter to the address above.

2\. Right to information and of complaint

You have the right to information about your stored personal data as per Art.15 GDPR (§34 BDSG), to removal of your data as per Art. 17 GDPR (§35 BDSG), and to correction of your data as per Art. 16 GDPR. Please submit your request in writing or via a (verified) email address using the aforementioned contact details.

In addition, you have a general right of complaint. The responsible supervisory authority for complaints regarding the data processing of Paessler AG is the Bavarian Data Protection Authority.

3\. Right to revocation of consent

If the data processing is based on consent, this consent can be revoked at any time with effect for the future. Submit your revocation in writing or via a (verified) email address using the aforementioned contact details.

### B - DATA PROCESSING UPON VISITING THE WEBSITE

1\. For the technical provision of the website (§15 par. 1 TMG)

Each time a user accesses a page of this web presence and each time a file is retrieved, data on these operations is stored in a logfile. This data includes the page from which the request originated (if communicated by your browser), the name of the requested file, the date and time of the request, the amount of data transferred, the notification if the request was successful, the description of the browser type used (if communicated by your browser), and the IP address of the machine forwarding the request. The storage of this data exclusively serves internal, system-related, and statistical purposes. 

2\. For pseudonymized use analysis and advertising success measurement (§15 par. 3 TMG)

This website uses various third-party services to create pseudonymized or anonymous information about the way the website is used and to better match content offers to users. For this purpose, pseudonymized data about the page usage such as the time, duration, and type of the page request, as well as information about the browsers, regional origin, and technology used is transmitted to the respective service. For further details, including the possibility to object, see the specific service. 

Google Analytics: Web analytics service of Google Inc. ("Google"). Information about your use of this website is transmitted to a Google server in the USA, where it is stored and used to generate anonymized reports on the use of the website and activities within the online offer. We would like to point out that on this website, Google Analytics has been extended by the code "get._anonymizeIP ();" to ensure an anonymized collection of IP addresses.

You can object to this data processing by installing or allowing an opt-out cookie that prevents data transmission. Alternatively, you can install an extension in your browser that prevents data transfer. Such an extension can be downloaded here <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en>.

Kissmetrics: This website uses Kissmetrics, a web analytics service of Space Pencil, Inc. Kissmetrics only uses first-party cookies, which can be removed by deleting your browser cookies. You can disable Kissmetrics tracking by using the opt-out link on the Kissmetrics website: <http://www.kissmetrics.com/user-privacy>.

Optimizely: This website uses Optimizely, a web analytics service of Optimizely Inc. that is used for A / B and multivariate tests. This service uses cookies to identify a visitor's browser and to analyze the use of this website. These cookies do not collect personal data. For more information on how Optimizely processes your data, visit <http://www.optimizely.com/privacy>. You can disable Optimizely tracking at any time by following the instructions at <http://www.optimizely.com/opt_out>.

HubSpot: This website uses HubSpot, a marketing automation platform of HubSpot, Inc.. Hubspot uses cookies that track a user’s interaction with Paessler websites. Hubspot also tracks browser-provided information such as inferred region, IP address, and return visits. Users remain anonymous unless the user has provided personal information through the submission of a form. HubSpot might be connected to other services and receive data from such services. See also section C. 3. To set an opt-out cookie, click here: [set opt-out cookie](https://www.paessler.com/company/privacypolicy#hubspot)

Amazon, Facebook, Instagram, LinkedIn, Twitter, Amazon, Outbrain, Reach Group, Reddit: On our website we use the remarketing pixel from multiple social media platforms. These pixels mark you as a visitor on our website in an anonymized form, without identifying you as a person and allows us the opportunity to retarget you with advertising while you are using these social media services. To be removed from the various remarketing user groups, please use the following opt-out links:

  * Facebook/Instagram: <https://www.facebook.com/ads/preferences/edit/>
  * LinkedIn: <https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/62931?lang=en>
  * Twitter: <https://twitter.com/personalization>
  * Amazon: <https://www.amazon.com/adprefs>
  * Outbrain: <https://my.outbrain.com/recommendations-settings/profile>
  * Reach Group: <https://www.reachgroup.com/en/opt-out/>
  * Reddit: [https://www.reddit.com/personalization](https://old.reddit.com/personalization "Verknüpfung folgen")

Hotjar: We use Hotjar to analyze the usage of our website. Hotjar will capture specific data related to the viewer's interaction with that particular webpage completely anonymous and by random selection. We do not record keypresses or the content of form fields with HotJar. You can deactivate HotJar by following the instructions on <https://www.hotjar.com/opt-out>.

apartena.metrics: This website uses apartena.metrics, a web analytics service of Burda Direct interactive GmbH. This service uses cookies to identify a visitor's browser and to analyze the use of this website. These cookies do not collect personal data. For more information on how apartena.metrics processes your data, visit <https://www.apartena.net/datenschutzerklaerung.html>. You can disable apartena.metrics tracking at any time by following the instructions at <https://metrics.apartena.net/privacy-optout.do>.

3\. For pseudonymized advertising (§15 par. 3 TMG)

Google Ads: Advertisements by means of cookies: You can be recognized as a visitor of the website, without your identity being known, via the set cookies so that when you visit other websites, the corresponding advertisements are displayed. In addition, internet users with specific profiles of interest based on their internet usage might be shown the corresponding advertisements. We do not collect any personal data with our cookies or other anonymous IDs. You can object to the collection and use of your data by Google Analytics at any time with effect for the future by making the appropriate Google settings.

4\. To integrate social media platforms

Our website uses social media plugins from Facebook, Twitter, Google, LinkedIn, and Share. Your IP address will not be forwarded automatically. It will only be sent, if you click one of the plugins (two-click solution).

### C - DATA PROCESSING UPON USE OF THE INDIVIDUAL WEB SERVICES

1\. When registering for the newsletter

When registering for the newsletter, we collect and store the provided email address and name to send you information about our products, new features, and offers. Your email address is not used for other purposes or passed on to third parties.

Your consent to the use of your email address for receiving our newsletter can be revoked at any time with effect for the future by clicking the "Unsubscribe" link at the end of the newsletter.

2\. When purchasing and installing trial and freeware (Art. 6 par. 1 lit. b and f GDPR)

For the use of trial and freeware and their operation, we collect and store your email address. Paessler uses this information to send you your license key, to guide you through the installation, to clarify typical questions that arise during installation, and to clarify the status of the installation. This is necessary for purposes of determining and correcting the support requirement during the installation and operation of the software, and to clarify the further use after the end of the test phase, whereby a contact can also be established by telephone (Art. 6 par. 1 lit. b GDPR). In order to ensure optimal support, contacting can also take place by partners or service providers assigned by us (Art. 6 par. 1 lit. f GDPR). Telephone numbers are only collected from publicly available sources.

3\. When using contact forms (Art. 6 par. 1 lit. b GDPR)

HubSpot: When filling in a form, your e-mail address, further given data as well as the details of your request will be collected and processed. The data are processed with the help of the service provider HubSpot and we store them for 12 months. After this period your data will be deleted unless you have been in contact with Paessler AG by e.g. visiting the a website of Paessler AG, downloading content, sending us an email etc.

Wufoo: We also use the form service Wufoo. It processes and stores the content that you enter into a contact form. Depending on the type of contact form, this may regard the following content: company, name, email address, telephone number, preferred supplier, invoice number, credit card details, t-shirt size, GitHub repository, and PRTG account email. The content will only be processed and saved when you submit a form. For more information about Wufoo's privacy policy, visit <https://www.wufoo.com/privacy/>.

4\. When registering for online training (Art. 6 par. 1 lit. b GDPR)

When registering for an online training, your e-mail address, first and last name and information about your company are collected and processed. The data are forwarded to the company ClassMarker Pty Ltd., which provides the service technically. For more information on ClassMarker's privacy policy, visit <https://www.classmarker.com/online-testing/privacy/>.

To collect the training fee we use the service of PayPal.

5\. When registering an account for our knowledge base  (Art. 6 par. 1 lit. b GDPR)

When you register for our knowledge base, we store your email address and other data you provide. Registration is independent from any other service. A registration is only necessary, if you want to write a question. You can send the question to our support team as an alternative.

### D - DATA PROCESSING UPON PURCHASE OF SOFTWARE / SERVICES

1\. For registration / account use (Art. 6 par. 1 lit. b GDPR)

During the purchase of a service, an email address and a password are used to set up an account ("registration"). The data are used to provide you access to your orders and contracts and to process the software purchase.

Upon registration and each time a registered user logs in, session cookies are stored on your machine in order to make the visit to our website more appealing and to enable the use of certain functions. These do not include any personal data, only your session ID, which is assigned to you during your visit. This session ID is used to reference internally stored data, such as information on the contents of your shopping cart so that if you visit our website at a later time, you can comfortably continue shopping. The generated cookies have an expiration time of 90 days.

2\. To process the order (Art. 6 par. 1 lit. b GDPR)

During the ordering process, we collect and store information about your identity and your contact details (in particular, your first and last name, address, telephone number, and email address), as well as information about your purchase and payment method, including bank or credit card data.

This information is used to complete the order, including payment, and to provide the software and purchased services. This includes providing updates so that you can download the most recent version of the software at any time, free of charge, and providing upgrade offers and other services of Paessler AG.

Your email address is also required to review your license and provide you with registration keys or download links, as well as to inform you about the status of maintenance contracts.

Within the ordering process, we use the popular Transport Layer Security (TLS) encryption method in conjunction with the highest encryption level supported by your browser. Typically, this is 256-bit encryption. If your browser does not support 256-bit encryption, we will use 128-bit technology instead. A closed lock or a key symbol in the status bar of your browser denotes whether a single page of our website is encrypted.

SaleCycle: Our shop uses SaleCycle to send an email with a cart reminder to users who do not complete their checkout and already provided their email address in the checkout process. (<http://www.salecycle.com/privacy-policy/>)

SendGrid: To reliably send the invoice and licence emails, we use the service of SendGrid. (<https://sendgrid.com/policies/privacy/)>.

3\. For payment transactions (Art. 6 par. 1 lit. b GDPR)

Your address and your payment information will be sent to the executing payment and billing service providers:

For PRTG hosted by Paessler, credit card information is processed by Stripe Inc. Headquarters, 185 Berry Street, Suite 550, San Francisco, CA 94107, USA. For more information on Stripe's privacy policy, please visit: <https://stripe.com/us/privacy>. Invoicing is processed by Chargebee Inc., 340 S. Lemon Ave # 1537, Walnut, CA, 91789, USA. For more information about Chargebee's privacy policy, please visit: <https://www.chargebee.com/privacy.html>. 

For PRTG on premises, the credit card information is processed by the payment service provider Computop Wirtschaftsinformatik GmbH, Schwarzenbergstr. 4, 96050 Bamberg, Germany; the acquirer Concardis GmbH, Helfmann-Park 7, 65760 Eschborn, Germany; and American Express Payment Services Europe Limited, Theodor-Heuss-Allee 112, 60486 Frankfurt am Main, Germany.

4\. For credit assessment and payment delay (Art. 6 par. 1 lit. b and f GDPR)

When paying via invoice, a credit assessment check is carried out before this type of payment is granted due to prevailing justifiable protection of interests. For this purpose, information about your creditworthiness is collected from credit agencies and used for evaluation purposes. If you object to the collection of your credit information, please choose another payment method.

If your payment is delayed, we reserve the right to transfer your personal data to a debt collection agency or to a law firm commissioned by us to ensure the collection of the outstanding amounts. This data transfer is subject to the requirements as per § 28a BDSG.

### E - DATA PROCESSING UPON USING SOFTWARE / SERVICES

1\. For software updates and generation of usage statistics

Software products from Paessler AG can periodically connect to Paessler AG servers to check for newer software versions or important security updates. During this connection, statistical information about the installation (for example, sensor count) is transmitted. We store and analyze this statistical data to make informed optimizations of or products and processes. 

We also use Google Analytics to collect statistical information about the use of the graphical user interfaces of PRTG to improve the user experience. This information is transmitted to a Google server in the USA, where it is stored and used to generate anonymized reports. The user can terminate or resume his/her participation in this statistical data collection at any time by turning this function off or on in the PRTG settings. For PRTG hosted by Paessler the user can use the opt-out mechanism described in section B.2.

We also generate statistics about the actual use of our software products and apps for mobile devices. This can provide us with valuable information for the continuous development of our products.

2\. For PRTG Added Services

Paessler may provide added services through third parties. As soon as these functions are used in a PRTG interface (including our apps), or via the API, the PRTG Core Server will connect to external infrastructure that is owned by Paessler without any further query.

In the case of using push notifications, Paessler AG stores necessary data (for example, a unique recipient ID and details about an alarm) and passes it on to other service providers (e.g. to Google, Apple, or Microsoft) to transmit it to end devices.  

In the case of monitoring targets via the PRTG Added Services (e.g. Ping, HTTP), Paessler AG stores the host and internet addresses monitored (URLs).

3\. For contacting Paessler

In the case of contacting technical support or customer service by using our contact forms or by email, PRTG stores the data transmitted and the “support bundle”. 

4\. For chatting with Paessler

We use the chat service of Olark by Habla, Inc. 245 Ramona St. Palo Alto, CA 94301, which allows the users of the PRTG web interface (and other PRTG software clients) to chat directly with employees of [paessler.com](https://www.paessler.com/) and get questions answered. During the chat connection, we display the location, IP address, browser and website visited. We do not have access to this data after the connection has been terminated. For details on Olark's handling of your personal data and your rights in this regard, please refer to Olark's privacy policy here: <https://www.olark.com/pages/tos>.

Olark places cookies on your computer. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser, however please note that if you do this you may not be able to use the live chat functionality of your web interface.

5\. For advertising purposes (Art. 6 par. 1 lit. f GDPR)

Paessler uses your data and your email address to provide you with offers for other services and products. In order to ensure optimal customer support, the contact can also be established by partners or service providers assigned by us. You can object to the establishment of contact at any time. Please send a complaint to [[email protected]](https://www.paessler.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#d4a7b5b8b1a794a4b5b1a7a7b8b1a6fab7bbb9).

We use TrustPilot as our customer review service. We add personalized URLs to some emails and webpages. Only when you click on such a link, your name and email address is transferred to TrustPilot. TrustPilot will only store your data, if you choose to create an account. (<http://legal.trustpilot.com/end-user-privacy-terms>)
